nomachine.com 2019-04-23

# NoMachine - NoMachine's Privacy Policy

This Policy applies to the NoMachine.com website, including the store (collectively referred to as the “Website”), and also applies to all services that we offer in connection with your relationship with us as a customer, including via your use of our Website, your customer area and associated support services, public forums and mailing lists (collectively referred to as the “Services”). We may use this information for the following purposes:

  * \- Send you information about the products and services that you have purchased from us  
 
  * \- Perform direct sales activities in cases where legitimate interest is established  
 
  * \- Reply to a ‘Contact Request’ or other web forms you have completed on our website  
 
  * \- Follow up on incoming requests (customer support, emails, chats, or phone calls)  
 
  * \- Provide access to our Customer Support portal  
 
  * \- Perform contractual obligations such as technical assistance, order confirmation, license details, accounting activities,   
  subscription reminders  
 
  * \- Notify you about any disruptions to our services  
 
  * \- Contact you to conduct surveys about your opinion on our products and services  
 
  * \- Process a job application if you have sent us your CV

This Policy does not apply to any website, product or service of any third-party company even if the website links to (or from) our Website. Please always review the privacy practices of any third-party company before deciding whether to provide any information.

By using our Website or Services, you are accepting the practices described in this Policy. If you do not agree with this Policy, please delete all cookies from your browser cache after visiting our Website and do not visit or use our Website or Services. Your continued use of our Website or Services will signify your acceptance of this Policy.

**Collection and use of your Personal Data**

By using the NoMachine Services, NoMachine collects data as deemed appropriate for the fulfillment of the service. When using the Services we may collect data about you as described below.

**Payment Information  **  
When purchasing NoMachine products on the NoMachine website, NoMachine receives your billing address which is stored in your customer area and can be edited at any time.  

**Support tickets and the customer area**  
All customers, when purchasing a subscription, are obliged to provide an email address which we use to send you follow-ups to support tickets you submit to us, and to notify its recipient of software updates, security advisories and reminders of expiring subscriptions, or any changes to the services requested. By submitting your email address, you authorize us to send these email communications. These communications are not made for marketing purposes and cannot be opted-out of.

By submitting an enquiry via your customer area, you are authorizing us to correspond with you and accept that we may receive personal information that you decide to include in correspondence with us as content of your support ticket. This may also include logs from the software. Anything communicated by you online via the support portal is stored as part of the online support services we offer. Logs are deleted one week after the support enquiry is closed.

**Software logs**

When you submit a support enquiry, or a request for assistance via any of the applicable contact channels, we may request logs to allow our support team and developers to investigate thoroughly. These logs may contain IP addresses, usernames and computer names of the affected user sessions. It is possible to blank out the sensitive information before submitting for analysis. Such logs are hosted on the customer’s server and are not shared with NoMachine unless explicitly allowed by the customer. By uploading these logs to our secure file server, you authorize us to use your personal data exclusively for the requested purpose.

**Contact Request & Report Issues forms**  
When you submit a contact-request using the form here: <https://www.nomachine.com/contact-request> we ask for information such as name, email address, phone number and other details which are optional. By sending this you authorize us to use your personal data exclusively for the requested purpose.

When you submit a bug report via the link <https://www.nomachine.com/report-an-issue>, you can choose whether to provide us with an email address. By providing us with a valid email address, you authorize us to contact you regarding the issue you wish to report and to use the email address exclusively for the requested purpose.

**Mailing lists**

If you sign up to any of our [mailing lists](https://www.nomachine.com/mailing-lists) NoMachine Announce and NoMachine News which are used to communicate software releases and company news via email, we may also occasionally email you with information about offers or new services. You can also opt out of these email communications by using the unsubscribe link included in such communications.  

**NoMachine forums**  
By creating an account on our forums, you are providing us with an email address. This is not public, but if you upload photos or videos, add posts or comments, etc. on our Forums website (<https://forums.nomachine.com/>), the information can be read by anyone with access to the Forums site and used for purposes over which NoMachine or you have no control. If you wish to remove any data, including your account, please contact forum@nomachine.com.

**Website visitors**

To simply browse our Website, you are not required to provide any Personal Data. However, we may gather non-personally-identifiable information, such as the IP address of your last access and the language preference you may decide to set in order to browse the website, solely for the purposes of monitoring and improving our Website and Services. We will not share this information with third parties or use it to target any advertisements to you.

**Cookies and Web server logs**

“Cookies” are a feature of web browser software that allows web servers to recognise the computer used to access a website. Cookies can remember what information a computer accessed on one web page to streamline activities on related web pages and to make the online experience easier and more personalized. Log files are used to monitor, measure, analyse, improve, and troubleshoot our Services.

When a user sets a language preference and request to remember this setting on our website, we use a cookie. This is the only cookie that NoMachine uses on its website to customize your experience and keeps that setting for your next visit.

You can choose to disable cookies for our website if you prefer. In that case, your request for a specific language setting will last for the duration of the open browser session, and you can set it again next time you visit. We don’t use any other type of cookie that will ‘personalize’ the experience or target you during your time on our website. We utilise other technologies to collect non-personally-identifiable information from our Website. such as the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, IP addresses, links to/from any page, and time spent at our site.

This data is contained in our Web Server Logs to measure web traffic and usage activity on our Website for purposes of monitoring, troubleshooting and improving our Website and Services, to look for possible fraudulent activity, and to better understand the sources of traffic and transactions on our Website.

**Storing, sharing and disclosure of your Personal Data**

NoMachine does not sell or rent your Personal Data to marketers or third parties. NoMachine may disclose Personal Data it collects about you to trusted third parties who are integral to the operation of our Website and Services for a variety of purposes in connection with providing our Services and operating our Website. These third parties may include our agents, contractors, financial institutions, payment processors, verification services and credit bureaus, as well as any third parties that you have directly authorised to receive your Personal Data.

We may store your Personal Data in locations outside the direct control of NoMachine, for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers. Some of the trusted third parties to whom we disclose your Personal Data are located outside of Luxembourg. These countries may include the United States of America and the United Kingdom.

We may also disclose your Personal Data to law enforcement, government officials, or other third parties if required by law or we believe in good faith that the disclosure is necessary to prevent physical harm or financial loss, to report suspected illegal activity, or to investigate violations of our Terms of Service.

If we are subject to a merger or acquisition with/by another company, we may share information with them in accordance with our global privacy standards. Should such an event occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this privacy notice with respect to your Personal Data. If we intend to handle your Personal Data for any purposes not covered in this privacy notice, you will receive prior notification of the processing of your Personal Data for the new purposes.

Any sharing or disclosure of your Personal Data will be in compliance with applicable EU data protection laws and regulations.

**How long we keep your Personal Data**

We retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide the Services you have requested, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our policies.

**Protection of Personal Data**

Although no data transmission can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, we take all reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Data we collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete, up-to-date, relevant and stored securely.

We also take all reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Data we hold is protected from misuse, interference, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure by the use of various methods including access limitation, and industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology to safeguard the account registration process and sign-up information. Other security safeguards include but are not limited to data encryption, firewalls, and physical access controls to building and files.

NoMachine maintains strict administrative, technical and physical procedures to protect information stored in our servers. Access to information is limited (through user/password credentials and software systems) to those employees who require it to perform their job functions.

We reserve the right to make changes to this Policy from time to time. If any changes are material and/or retroactive, we may provide additional notice and/or an opportunity to “opt-in” or “opt-out” as appropriate under the circumstances. We may also advise you of changes to this policy by emailing the revised policy to any email addresses you provide us. Any changes willl be compliant with applicable EU data protection laws and regulations.

**Access, correction and complaints – Contact Us**

If you have any questions or suggestions about this Privacy Policy or would like to access, seek correction of or remove your Personal Data, or if you have complaints regarding our privacy practices, please contact us by emailing privacy@nomachine.com.
